Register of the Alexander Vardy Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS, 1940-2002 (Box 128)
  - Speeches and writings, 1962-1989
    - General
      - "Na filosofskom Kongresse," Soobshchenia instituta po izucheniu SSSR, 1968. (Folder 130: 7)
      - Speech, 14th International Congress of Philosophy, Vienna, 1968. (Folder 130: 8)
      - "Materialisticheskaia dialektika i sovremennoe estestvoznanie" Posev, 1968 March. (Folder 130: 9)
      - "Sblizhenie zapada i vostoka," Posev, 1968 July. (Folder 130: 10)
      - "O dialektike kommunisticheskoi filosofii," Soobshchenia instituta po izucheniu SSSR, 1969. (Folder 130: 11)
      - "Il leninismo e la scienza nell'URSS," Sovietica (Edizioni scientifiche italiane), 1969 October. (Folder 130: 12)
      - "Party Control over Soviet Science," Studies of the Soviet Union (Bulletin: Institute for the Study of the USSR), 1970. (Folder 130: 13)
      - "Lenin, lenintsy, leninizm i razvitie sovetskoi nauki," Vozrozhdenie, 1970 April. (Folder 130: 14)
      - "Kto zhe vse-taki 'glupets' i kto 'providets'?" Zarubezh'e, 1970 June. (Folder 130: 15)
      - "Rossia bez prikras i umolchanii," Zarubezh'e, Review of L. Vladimirov, Rossia bez prikras i umolchanii, 1969., 1970 June. (Folder 130: 16)
      - "Dialektika I sovremennoe nauchnoe mirovozzrenie," Vozrozhdenie, 1970 September. (Folder 130: 17)
      - "Pravda i lozh' kommunisma," Zarubezh'e, 1970 December. (Folder 131: 1)
      - "Na ch'ei storone D. P. Konchalovskii?" Zarubezh'e, 1971 March. (Folder 131: 2)
      - "Biologicheskie nauki dobivaiut marxsizm-leninizm," Vozrozhdenie, 1971 April. (Folder 131: 3)
      - "Diamat i sovremennaia nauka," Posev, 1971 July. (Folder 131: 4)
      - "Nauka razvenchivaet marxsizm-leninizm," Zarubezh'e, 1971 September-December. (Folder 131: 5)
      - "Biologia protiv rukovodstva KPSS," Vozrozhdenie, 1971 October. (Folder 131: 6)
      - "'Teoreticheskii front' KPSS I peredovye biologi," Posev, 1971 December. (Folder 131: 7)
      - "Zagovor propiv psikhiki," Vozrozhdenie, 1973 May. (Folder 131: 8)
      - "Die Erziehung zum Hab," 24 Zengen: Documente des Terrors, Sacharow-Hearing Kopenhagen, 1975. (Folder 131: 9)
      - "O roli psikhicheskikh faktorov v istorii," Zarubezh'e, 1975 June-September. (Folder 131: 10)
      - "Narushenie prav cheloveka v SSSR v sfere vospitania," Zarubezh'e, 1975 December. (Folder 131: 11)
      - "An Education in Hate," The International Sakharov Hearing, 1976. (Folder 131: 12)
      - Speech, The International Sakharov Hearing, Munich, 1976. (Folder 131: 13)
        Typescript. Includes correspondence and clippings
      - "Pis'mo v redaktsiu," Golos Zarubezh'ia, 1976 January. (Folder 131: 14)
      - "O trekh aktual'nykh kommunisticheskikh mifakh," Golos Zarubezh'ia, 1976 December. (Folder 131: 15)
        Printed copy and typescript
      - "Die Moskauer Lüge von 20 Millionen Kriegstoten widerlegt," Deutschland-Magazin, 1977. (Folder 131: 16)
      - "Zdenek Mlyharzh o 'Prazhskoi vesne'," Russkaia mysl', 1978 February. (Folder 131: 17)
      - "K 60-letiu I. Kachurovskogo," Seiatel', 1979. (Folder 131: 18)
      - "K sobytiam v Pol'she," Golos Zarubezh'ia, 1981 March. (Folder 131: 19)
      - Manlacht nicht nur in Eriwan, Düsseldorf, 1984. (Folder 131: 20)
      - "Die Verluste der Sowjetunion: 20 Millionen?" America Woche, 1984. (Folder 131: 21)
      - "Chernobyl' ...pochemu?" Almanac Panorama, 1986. (Folder 131: 22)
      - "Napadki na Prezidenta - Pochemu?" Almanac Panorama, 1986. (Folder 131: 23)
      - "SSSR poterial 20 millionov chelovek?" Panorama, 1986. (Folder 131: 24)
      - "Tragedia v Karachi... pochemu?" Almanac Panorama, 1986. (Folder 131: 25)
      - "Vozmozhno li arabo-evreiskoe gosudarstvo," Almanac Panorama, 1986. (Folder 131: 26)
      - "Chem vyzvan vykhod KGB na avanstsenu vlasti?" Almanac Panorama, 1986 December. (Folder 131: 27)
      - "Kakoi kommunism privnesen v Rossiu?" Almanac Panorama, 1987. (Folder 131: 28)
      - "K mifu o privnesennom kommunisme," Almanac Panorama, 1987. (Folder 132: 1)
      - "Komu v SSSR nuzhna diktatura?" Panorama, 1987. (Folder 132: 2)
      - "Ne tot drug, kto medom mazhet...," Almanac Panorama, 1987 July. (Folder 132: 3)
      - "Osnovnaia oshibka Marksa," Panorama, 1987 November. (Folder 132: 4)
      - "Bez tufty i ugovora ne vsuchish' dogovora," Almanac Panorama, 1988. (Folder 132: 5)
      - "Kazennyi koren' 'Pamiati'," Almanac Panorama, 1988. (Folder 132: 6)
      - Letter to the editor, Panorama, 1988. (Folder 132: 7)
      - "M. Begin i I. Shamir - terroristy?" Panorama, 1988. (Folder 132: 8)
      - "Sverkhpribyli i ideologia," Almanac Panorama, 1988. (Folder 132: 9)
      - Letter to the editor, Panorama, 1989. (Folder 132: 10)
    - About Jews
      - "Otvety na navety,", n.d. (Folder 132: 11)
      - "Evrei v Sovetskom Soiuze," Posev, 1967 September. (Folder 132: 12)
      - "70 let v sovetskoi nevole," (?)., 1987 (Folder 132: 13)
  - Radio Liberty general file. Clippings (Folder 132: 14)
  - Soviet labor camps file. Songs, general (Folder 132: 15)
  - Nomi Vardy (Sofia Antonova Perets) file, 1994-2002
    - Order of merit, 1994 (Folder 132: 16)
    - Writings
      - Tell Me, Grandma, Vantage Press, Inc., New York, 1999 (Folder 132: 17)
      - Good-Bye, Milky Way: Fables of the Third Millennium, Vantage Press, Inc., New York, 2001 (Folder 132: 18)
      - Ward 13, Trafford Publishing, Victoria, Canada, 2002 (Folder 132: 19)